ONOME OVIERO

SOFTWARE/ FRONTEND DEVELOPER

onomeoviero@gmail.com || GitHub || LinkedIn || Medium

SUMMARY

Dedicated and creative Developer with about 2 years of experience and background in Mathematics and fluency in both French and English language. Ready to work as a team to develop, test, and maintain software applications and solutions.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Bulma

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS Remote

Frontend Web Developer

Sept 2021 - Present

<u>Image-Gallery</u>- A responsive image gallery.

• Built with: (HTML5 and CSS3)

Bookstore App — This app helps the users to know if selected books are available, borrowed, or sold.

• Built with: (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)

Sign-in App — This produces a card that shows the details of the user.

- Built with: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- <u>React-world App</u> This gives a summarised detail about any selected country in the world.
 Built with: (React, API, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)

Getmobile

Frontend Developer

Jan, 2022 - Till date

- Worked with senior developer to carry out projects as assigned.
- Frequently updated the product and project managers on the software developmental stage.
- · Attended meetings as schedulled.

SKILLUP AFRICA

Frontend Web Developer

Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

- Worked in collaboration with teammates to produce the expected results.
- Gained excellent soft skills and completed projects as expected.
- Learned new professional skills and was able to successfully attend scheduled meetings.

CINFORES NIGERIA LTD.

Software and Network Technician

Sept 2014 - May 2015

- Successfully carried-out all assigned tasks.
- Supported company policies, procedures, mission, standards of ethics, and integrity.

EDUCATION

UNIVELCITY Frontend Development(React.Js)

Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

- Spent 120+ hours mastering JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bulma, React, data structures, and frontend development while simultaneously developing projects.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ENUGU STATE UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

BSc. Mathematics

March 2004 - Dec 2008

• Coursework included: calculus, linear and abstract algebra, Mathematical modeling, differentiation, and so on.